So I've been "futuring," which is a term I made up --
لقد كنت "مُستقبلي" وهو مصطلح قمت باختراعه --
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
about three seconds ago.
منذ ثلاث ثوانٍ تقريبًا.
I've been futuring for about 20 years,
إنني كذلك منذ قرابة عشرين عامًا،
and when I first started, I would sit down with people,
وحين بدأت بذلك، كنت أجلس مع الناس،
and say, "Hey, let's talk 10, 20 years out."
وأقول: "مرحبًا، دعنا نتحدث عن عشر أو عشرين سنة من الآن."
And they'd say, "Great."
وهم يقولون: "عظيم."
And I've been seeing that time horizon
ومن ثم أرى ذلك الأفق الزمني
get shorter and shorter
يصبح أقصر وأقصر
and shorter,
وأقصر،
so much so that I met with a CEO two months ago
لدرجة أني قابلت أحد المدراء التنفيذيين منذ شهرين
and I said -- we started our initial conversation.
وقلت -- بدأنا بمحادثتنا الأولية.
He goes, "I love what you do. I want to talk about the next six months."
بدأ هو بالحديث: "أحب ما تقوم به. أريد التحدث عن الأشهر الستة القادمة."
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
We have a lot of problems that we are facing.
تواجهنا العديد من المشاكل.
These are civilizational-scale problems.
مشاكل على المستوى الحضاري.
The issue though is,
إلا أن المسألة هي
we can't solve them
أننا لن نتمكن من حل تلك المشكلات
using the mental models that we use right now
من خلال النماذج الذهنية التي نستخدمها حاليًا
to try and solve these problems.
في محاولة لحل هذه المشاكل.
Yes, a lot of great technical work is being done,
نعم، الكثير من العمل يتم انجازه،
but there is a problem that we need to solve for a priori, before,
لكن هناك معضلة نحن بحاجة إلى حلها مسبقًا، قبل ذلك،
if we want to really move the needle on those big problems.
إذا أردنا حقًا أن نصنع فرقًا بخصوص هذه المشاكل الضخمة
"Short-termism."
"التفكير قصير المدى"
Right? There's no marches. There's no bracelets.
صحيح؟ لا توجد مسيرات. لا توجد قيود
There's no petitions that you can sign to be against short-termism.
لا توجد عرائض نستطيع توقيعها ضد التفكير قصير المدى.
I tried to put one up, and no one signed.
حاولت أن أعد واحدة، ولم يوقّعها أحد.
It was weird.
لقد كان الأمر غريبًا.
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
But it prevents us from doing so much.
لكنه يمنعنا من أن نقوم بالكثير.
Short-termism, for many reasons,
التفكير قصير المدى، ولأسباب عدة،
has pervaded every nook and cranny of our reality.
تخلل كل جوانب حياتنا.
I just want you to take a second
أريد منكم أن تأخذوا ثانية
and just think about an issue that you're thinking, working on.
وتفكروا بمسألة تشغل بالكم، تعملون عليها.
It could be personal, it could be at work
قد تكون شخصية، قد تتعلق بالعمل
or it could be move-the-needle world stuff,
أو مسألة تصنع فرقًا في العالم،
and think about how far out you tend to think
وتأملوا المدى الذي تعودتم بالتفكير خلاله
about the solution set for that.
بحثًا عن مجموعة الحلول لذلك.
Because short-termism prevents the CEO
لأن التفكير قصير المدى يمنع المدير التنفيذي
from buying really expensive safety equipment.
من شراء معدات أمان باهظة الثمن.
It'll hurt the bottom line.
ستؤذي المجموع النهائي.
So we get the Deepwater Horizon.
فنحصل على حادثة (ديب واتر هورايزن).
Short-termism prevents teachers
التفكير قصير المدى يحرم المدرسين
from spending quality one-on-one time with their students.
من إمضاء وقت مخصص فردًا لفرد مع تلاميذهم.
So right now in America,
ولهذا في أمريكا حاليًا،
a high school student drops out every 26 seconds.
يترك طالب في الثانوية المدرسة كل 26 ثانية.
Short-termism prevents Congress --
التفكير قصير المدى يمنع الكونغرس --
sorry if there's anyone in here from Congress --
آسف إذا كان أحد من الكونغرس هنا --
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
or not really that sorry --
أو لعلّي لست آسفًا حقًا --
from putting money into a real infrastructure bill.
من صرف الأموال على بنى تحتية حقيقية.
So what we get is the I-35W bridge collapse
وما نحصل عليه هو انهيار جسر I-35W
over the Mississippi a few years ago,
فوق نهر المسيسيبي منذ بضع سنوات،
13 killed.
قُتل 13 شخصا.
It wasn't always like this. We did the Panama Canal.
لما يكن الأمر هكذا دائمًا. لقد أنشأنا قناة بنما.
We pretty much have eradicated global polio.
اقتربنا بشدة من القضاء على شلل الأطفال عالميًا.
We did the transcontinental railroad, the Marshall Plan.
أنجزنا سكة حديد عابرة للقارات، مشروع مارشال.
And it's not just big, physical infrastructure problems and issues.
إنها ليست القضايا والمشاكل الكبيرة المادية للبنية التحتية فحسب.
Women's suffrage, the right to vote.
حق المرأة في الاقتراع، حق التصويت.
But in our short-termist time,
لكن في عصر التفكير قصير المدى،
where everything seems to happen right now
حيث يبدو أن كل شيء يحصل للتّو
and we can only think out past the next tweet or timeline post,
وأبعد ما نستطيع التفكير به هو التغريدة أو المنشور القادم،
we get hyper-reactionary.
نصبح رجعيّين بشدة.
So what do we do?
ماذا نفعل إذًا؟
We take people who are fleeing their war-torn country,
نأخذ الذين هربوا من بلدهم التي مزقتها الحرب،
and we go after them.
ونلاحقهم.
We take low-level drug offenders, and we put them away for life.
نأخذ مجرمي المخدرات من المستوى المنخفض، ونسجنهم مدى الحياة.
And then we build McMansions without even thinking
ومن ثم نبني قصورًا فارهة للتباهي دون حتى أن نفكر
about how people are going to get between them and their job.
كيف سيتنقّل الناس بين منازلهم وأعمالهم.
It's a quick buck.
إنه ربح سريع.
Now, the reality is, for a lot of these problems,
الآن، الواقع فيما يتعلق بالعديد من هذه المشاكل،
there are some technical fixes,
توجد بعض الإصلاحات التقنية،
a lot of them.
الكثير منها.
I call these technical fixes sandbag strategies.
أسمّي هذه الإصلاحات التقنية استراتيجيات كيس الرمل.
So you know there's a storm coming,
أنت تعلم بقدوم عاصفة،
the levee is broken, no one's put any money into it,
السور محطم، لا أحد يقوم باصلاحه،
you surround your home with sandbags.
تحيط منزلك بأكياس الرمل.
And guess what? It works.
وتصوّروا ماذا؟ إنها تنجح.
Storm goes away, the water level goes down,
ترحل العاصفة، ينخفض مستوى الماء،
you get rid of the sandbags,
تتخلص من أكياس الرمل،
and you do this storm after storm after storm.
وتفعل هذا عاصفة تلو عاصفة تلو عاصفة.
And here's the insidious thing.
والشيء المغوي بالأمر،
A sandbag strategy
أن استراتيجية كيس الرمل
can get you reelected.
ستعيد انتخابك.
can help you make your quarterly numbers.
ستساعدك على تحقيق أرباح ربع السنة.
Now, if we want to move forward
الآن، إذا أردت التقدم
into a different future than the one we have right now,
نحو مستقبل مختلف عمّا في ذهنك،
because I don't think we've hit --
لأني لا أظن أننا بلغنا --
2016 is not peak civilization.
2016 ليست ذروة الحضارة.
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
There's some more we can do.
ما زال هناك المزيد لنفعله.
But my argument is that unless we shift our mental models and our mental maps
لكن يكمن محور الجدال في أننا إن لم نغيّر نماذجنا وخرائطنا الذهنية
on how we think about the short,
فيما يتعلق بالتفكير قريب الأمد،
it's not going to happen.
لن يحصل هذا.
So what I've developed is something called "longpath,"
قمت بتطوير شيء يدعى "الدرب الطويل،"
and it's a practice.
إنه تمرين.
And longpath isn't a kind of one-and-done exercise.
ليس الدرب الطويل تمرينًا لمرة واحدة.
I'm sure everyone here at some point has done an off-site
أنا متأكد أن الجميع هنا خصص مرةً ركنًا بعيدًا عن العمل
with a lot of Post-It notes and whiteboards,
علّق في الكثير من الملحوظات وألواح الكتابة،
and you do --
وأنتم --
no offense to the consultants in here who do that --
لا أقلل من شأن المستشارين هنا ممن يقوم بذلك --
and you do a long-term plan,
وتضعون خطة طويلة المدى،
and then two weeks later, everyone forgets about it.
ثم بعد أسبوعين، ينساها الجميع.
Right? Or a week later. If you're lucky, three months.
صحيح؟ أو بعد أسبوع. إذا كنتم محظوظين، ثلاثة أشهر.
It's a practice because it's not necessarily a thing that you do.
إنه تمرين لأنه ليس بالضرورة أمرًا تقوم به.
It's a process where you have to revisit different ways of thinking
إنه نهج يدعوك للتفكير بطرق مختلفة
for every major decision that you're working on.
أمام كل قرار مهم عليك اتخاذه.
So I want to go through those three ways of thinking.
أريد إذًا أن أمر بهذه الطرق الثلاث للتفكير.
So the first: transgenerational thinking.
الأول: التفكير العابر للأجيال.
I love the philosophers:
أحب الفلاسفة:
Plato, Socrates, Habermas, Heidegger.
أفلاطون، سقراط، هابرماس، هايدغر.
I was raised on them.
لقد نشأت على أيديهم.
But they all did one thing
لكنهم قاموا جميعًا بشيء واحد
that didn't actually seem like a big deal
لم يبدُ بالأمر المهم
until I really started kind of looking into this.
قبل أن أبدأ بالنظر في المسألة.
And they all took,
تم اعتبرهم جميعهم،
as a unit of measure for their entire reality
كوحدة لقياس واقعهم
of what it meant to be virtuous and good,
والذي توجّب أن تكون خيّرةً وفاضلة،
the single lifespan,
فترة حياة الفرد،
from birth to death.
من الولادة حتى الموت.
But here's a problem with these issues:
لكن هناك مشكلة مع هذه المسائل:
they stack up on top of us,
إنها تتراكم علينا،
because the only way we know how to do something good in the world
لأن الطريقة الوحيدة لمعرفة ما إذا قمنا بعمل حسن في هذا العالم
is if we do it between our birth and our death.
هي أن نقوم به ما بين الولادة والموت.
That's what we're programmed to do.
هذا ما نحن مبرمجون عليه.
If you go to the self-help section in any bookstore,
لو ذهبت إلى قسم "ساعد نفسك" في أي مكتبة،
it's all about you.
كل ما فيه يتحدث عنك.
Which is great,
وهذا عظيم،
unless you're dealing with some of these major issues.
ما لم تكن تتعامل مع بعض المعضلات الكبرى.
And so with transgenerational thinking,
وبهذا فإنك عبر التفكير العابر للأجيال،
which is really kind of transgenerational ethics,
والذي يمثل حقًا أخلاقياتٍ عابرة للأجيال،
you're able to expand how you think about these problems,
ستكون قادرًا على توسيع طريقة تفكيرك بهذه المشاكل،
what is your role in helping to solve them.
والتفكير بدورك في حلها.
Now, this isn't something that just has to be done at the Security Council chamber.
الآن، ليس هذا أمرًا يجدر تطبيقه في قاعة مجلس الأمن فقط.
It's something that you can do in a very kind of personal way.
إنه أمر تستطيع تطبيقه على منحى شخصي.
So every once in a while, if I'm lucky, my wife and I like to go out to dinner,
بين حين وآخر، إذا حالفني الحظ، أحب الذهاب مع زوجتي لتناول العشاء،
and we have three children under the age of seven.
ولدينا ثلاثة أطفال تحت سن السابعة،
So you can imagine it's a very peaceful, quiet meal.
لك أن تتخيل أنها وجبة مسالمة وهادئة جدًا.
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
So we sit down and literally all I want to do is just eat and chill,
نجلس سوية، وكل ما أريده حرفيًا أن آكل وأسترخي فحسب،
and my kids have a completely and totally different idea
لكن أطفالي لديهم فكرة مختلفة تمامًا
of what we're going to be doing.
عمّا ننوي فعله.
And so my first idea
إن أول فكرة تخطر ببالي
is my sandbag strategy, right?
هي استراتيجية كيس الرمل، صحيح؟
It's to go into my pocket and take out the iPhone
أن أدخل يدي في جيبي وأخرج هاتفي
and give them "Frozen"
وأعطيهم لعبة "Frozen"
or some other bestselling game thing.
أو إحدى الألعاب الأكثر مبيعًا.
And then I stop
ثم أتوقف
and I have to kind of put on this transgenerational thinking cap.
وأضع قبعة التفكير العابر للأجيال.
I don't do this in the restaurant, because it would be bizarre,
لا أفعل ذلك في المطعم، لأنه سيبدو غريبًا،
but I have to --
لكنني مضطر --
I did it once, and that's how I learned it was bizarre.
فعلت ذلك مرة، وحينها تعلمت أنه كان غريبًا.
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
And you have to kind of think, "OK, I can do this."
يجدر بك التفكير، "حسنًا، أستطيع فعل هذا."
But what is this teaching them?
ولكن ما الدرس الذي سيتعلمونه؟
So what does it mean if I actually bring some paper
ماذا قد يعني لو أنني أحضرت ورقة حقًا
or engage with them in conversation?
أو انخرطت معهم في مناقشة؟
It's hard. It's not easy, and I'm making this very personal.
إنه أمر صعب. ليس سهلًا، وأنا أجعل منه شخصيًا جدًا.
It's actually more traumatic
إنه في الحقيقة أكثر خطبًا
than some of the big issues that I work on in the world --
من بعض المسائل الكبيرة التي أعمل عليها في العالم --
entertaining my kids at dinner.
تسلية أطفالي خلال العشاء.
But what it does is it connects them here in the present with me,
لكن ما تفعله أنها تربطهم معي هنا في الحاضر،
but it also --
ولكنها أيضًا --
and this is the crux of transgenerational thinking ethics --
وهذا هو الجوهر الأخلاقي للتفكير العابر للأجيال --
it sets them up to how they're going to interact with their kids
إنها تحضّرهم للطريقة التي سيتعاملون فيها مع أطفالهم
and their kids and their kids.
ومع أطفالهم ومع أطفالهم.
Second, futures thinking.
ثانيًا، التفكير بالمستقبل،
When we think about the future,
إننا نفكر بالمستقبل،
10, 15 years out,
10، 15 سنة من الآن،
give me a vision of what the future is.
تصوروا كيف للمستقبل أن يكون.
You don't have to give it to me, but think in your head.
لا تخبروني بها، ولكن فكروا داخل رؤوسكم.
And what you're probably going to see
ما سترونه على الأرجح
is the dominant cultural lens
هو العدسة الثقافية المهيمنة
that dominates our thinking about the future right now:
التي تحكم نظرتنا عن المستقبل في هذه اللحظة:
technology.
التكنولوجيا.
So when we think about the problems,
ولذا فإننا حين نفكر بالمشاكل،
we always put it through a technological lens,
إننا ننظر للأمور دومًا عبر عدسة التكنولوجيا،
a tech-centric, a techno-utopia, and there's nothing wrong with that,
عالم محوره التكنولوجيا، جنة تكنولوجية، وليس من خطأ في ذلك،
but it's something that we have to really think deeply about
لكن أمر يحتاج إلى تفكير عميق
if we're going to move on these major issues,
إذا أردنا التقدم فيما يتعلق بتلك المشاكل الكبيرة،
because it wasn't always like this. Right?
فالأمر لم يكن كذلك دومًا. صحيح؟
The ancients had their way of thinking
امتلك القدماء طريقتهم في التفكير
about what the future was.
عمّا كان المستقبل.
The Church definitely had their idea of what the future could be,
كان للكنيسة فكرتها بالتأكيد عمّا يمكن أن يكون عليه المستقبل،
and you could actually pay your way into that future. Right?
وقد استطتعتم فعلًا دفع تكاليف ذلك المستقبل. صحيح؟
And luckily for humanity,
ولحسن حظ البشرية،
we got the scientific revolution.
حصلنا على الثورة العلمية.
From there, we got the technology,
ومن هناك، حصلنا على التكنولوجيا،
but what has happened --
ولكن ماذا حصل --
And by the way, this is not a critique.
وبالمناسبة، ليس هذا نقدًا.
I love technology.
أنا أحب التكنولوجيا.
Everything in my house talks back to me,
كل شيء في منزلي يتحدث إليّ
from my children to my speakers to everything.
من أطفالي إلى سماعاتي إلى كل شيء.
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
But we've abdicated the future from the high priests in Rome
لكننا أزلنا كبار كهنة روما عن عرش المستقبل
to the high priests of Silicon Valley.
لننصّب على عرشه قساوسة وادي السيليكون.
So when we think, well, how are we going to deal with climate
لذا فإننا حين نفكر، حسنًا، كيف سنتصرف حيال المناخ
or with poverty or homelessness,
أو حيال الفقر أو التشرد،
our first reaction is to think about it through a technology lens.
يكون رد فعلنا الأول هو التفكير عبر عدسة التكنولوجيا،
And look, I'm not advocating that we go to this guy.
انظروا، أنا لا أدعوكم للتوجه إلى هذا الشخص.
I love Joel, don't get me wrong,
أنا أحب جويل، لا تفهموني خطأً.
but I'm not saying we go to Joel.
ولكنني لا أقصد أن نذهب جويل.
What I'm saying is we have to rethink
ما أقصده أن علينا إعادة التفكير
our base assumption about only looking at the future in one way,
في افتراضنا الأساسي عن رؤية المستقبل بطريقة واحدة،
only looking at it through the dominant lens.
رؤيته عبر العدسة المهيمنة.
Because our problems are so big and so vast
لأن مشاكلنا كبيرة وضخمة جدًا
that we need to open ourselves up.
فنحن بحاجة لأن نصبح متفتحين.
So that's why I do everything in my power not to talk about the future.
ولهذا فإنني أحاول بكل ما أوتيت من قوة أن لا أتحدث عن المستقبل.
I talk about futures.
أنا أتحدث عن المستقبلات.
It opens the conversation again.
وهذا يفتح الحوار مجددًا.
So when you're sitting and thinking
ولذلك فإننا حين نجلس ونفكر
about how do we move forward on this major issue --
كيف نحقق تقدمًا فيما يتعلق بمشكلة عويصة --
it could be at home,
قد تكون في المنزل،
it could be at work,
قد تكون في العمل،
it could be again on the global stage --
قد تكون مجددًا على مستوى العالم --
don't cut yourself off from thinking about something beyond technology as a fix
لا تمنع نفسك من التفكير بحلٍ يتجاوز التكنولوجيا
because we're more concerned about technological evolution right now
لأننا في الوقت الحالي مهتمون بالتقدم التكنولوجي
than we are about moral evolution.
أكثر من اهتمامنا بالتقدم الأخلاقي.
And unless we fix for that,
وما لم نقم بإصلاح هذا،
we're not going to be able to get out of short-termism
لن نكون قادرين على أن نتخلص من التفكير قصير المدى
and get to where we want to be.
وأن نصل إلى هدفنا.
The final, telos thinking. This comes from the Greek root.
الأخير، التفكير الغائي. وهو من الجذور الإغريقية.
Ultimate aim and ultimate purpose.
الهدف الأسمى والغاية الأسمى.
And it's really asking one question:
وهو في الحقيقة يطرح سؤالًا واحدًا:
to what end?
إلى أية نهاية؟
When was the last time you asked yourself: To what end?
متى كانت آخر مرة سألت فيها نفسك: إلى أية نهاية؟
And when you asked yourself that, how far out did you go?
وحين سألت نفسك، إلى أي مدى وصلت؟
Because long isn't long enough anymore.
لأن البعيد لم يعد بعيدًا بما فيه الكفاية.
Three, five years doesn't cut it.
ثلاث أو خمس سنوات لا تجزم الأمر.
It's 30, 40, 50, 100 years.
إنها 30، 40، 50، 100 سنة.
In Homer's epic, "The Odyssey,"
في ملحمة (هوميروس)، "الأوديسة"
Odysseus had the answer to his "what end."
توجب على (أوديسيوس) أن يجيب على "أية نهاية" خاصته
It was Ithaca.
لقد كانت (إيثاكا).
It was this bold vision of what he wanted --
كانت تلك رؤيته الجريئة لما أراد --
to return to Penelope.
أن يعود إلى (بينيلوبي).
And I can tell you, because of the work that I'm doing,
وأستطيع إخباركم، بحكم العمل الذي أقوم به،
but also you know it intuitively -- we have lost our Ithaca.
ولكنكم تدركون هذا بحدسكم -- لقد خسرنا (إيثاكا) خاصتنا.
We have lost our "to what end," so we stay on this hamster wheel.
لقد خسرنا "إلى أية نهاية"، ولهذا لا نغادرعجلة الهامستر هذه.
And yes, we're trying to solve these problems,
نعم، نحن نحاول حل هذه المشاكل،
but what comes after we solve the problem?
ولكن ما الذي سيأتي بعد أن نفلح في حلّها؟
And unless you define what comes after, people aren't going to move.
ما لم نوضح ماذا سيتبع ذلك، لن يتحرك الناس.
The businesses -- this isn't just about business --
التجارة -- وليس هذا عن التجارة فحسب --
but the businesses that do consistently, who break out of short-termism
لكن الأعمال التي وباستمرار، تكسر حلقة التفكير قصير المدى
not surprisingly are family-run businesses.
وبشكل غير مفاجئ هي أعمال تسيرها العائلة.
They're transgenerational. They're telos. They think about the futures.
إنهم عابرون للأجيال. إنهم غائيون. إنهم يفكرون بالمستقبلات.
And this is an ad for Patek Philippe. They're 175 years old,
هذا إعلان لـ باتيك فيليب. يبلغون 175 سنة من العمر،
and what's amazing is that they literally embody
والأمر الرائع أنهم يجسدون حرفيًا
this kind of longpathian sense in their brand,
هذا النوع من الحس الممتد على الدرب في شعارهم،
because, by the way, you never actually own a Patek Philippe,
لأنه، وبالمناسبة، أنتم لن تمتلكوا ساعة (باتيك فيليب) مطلقًا،
and I definitely won't --
ولا أنا دون شك --
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
unless somebody wants to just throw 25,000 dollars on the stage.
إلا إذا أراد أحدهم أن يرمي 25.000 دولار على المسرح.
You merely look after it for the next generation.
أنتم بكل بساطة تعتنون بها لأجل الجيل القادم.
So it's important that we remember,
ولهذا فإن من المهم أن نتذكر،
the future, we treat it like a noun.
المستقبل، إننا نعامله وكأنه اسم.
It's not. It's a verb.
إنه ليس كذلك. إنه فعل.
It requires action.
يحتاج مبادرة.
It requires us to push into it.
يحتاج أن ندفع باتجاهه.
It's not this thing that washes over us.
إنه ليس بالأمر الذي يداهمنا.
It's something that we actually have total control over.
إنه أمر نملك التحكم التام به.
But in a short-term society, we end up feeling like we don't.
ولكن في مجتمع قصير الأمد، ننتهي إلى الشعور بالعكس.
We feel like we're trapped.
نشعر بأننا محاصرون.
We can push through that.
يمكننا التغلب على ذلك.
Now I'm getting more comfortable
أشعرالآن بارتياح أكبر
in the fact that at some point
مؤمنًا بحقيقة أنني عند مرحلة معيّنة
in the inevitable future,
في المستقبل المحتوم،
I will die.
سوف أموت.
But because of these new ways of thinking and doing,
لكن بفضل هذه الطرق الجديدة في التفكير والفعل،
both in the outside world and also with my family at home,
في العالم الخارجي ومع عائلتي في المنزل على حد سواء،
and what I'm leaving my kids, I get more comfortable in that fact.
وفي ما سأتركه لأطفالي، أصبح أكثر ارتياحًا مع هذه الحقيقة.
And it's something that a lot of us are really uncomfortable with,
وهو أمر يراه الكثيرون غير مريح حقًا،
but I'm telling you,
ولكنني أخبركم،
think it through.
فكروا بالأمر مليًا.
Apply this type of thinking and you can push yourself past
طبّقوا هذا النمط من التفكير وستتمكنون من تخطي
what's inevitably very, very uncomfortable.
كل أمر محتوم مزعج جدًا جدًا.
And it all begins really with yourself asking this question:
وكل ذلك يبدأ حقًا بطرح هذا السؤال على أنفسكم:
What is your longpath?
ما هو دربك الطويل؟
But I ask you, when you ask yourself that
لكنني أطلب منكم، حين تسألون أنفسكم
now or tonight or behind a steering wheel
الآن أو الليلة أو خلف عجلة القيادة
or in the boardroom or the situation room:
أو في غرفة الاجتماعات أو غرفة القرارات:
push past the longpath,
تخطوا الدرب الطويل،
quick, oh, what's my longpath the next three years or five years?
بسرعة، آه، ما هو دربي الطويل في السنوات الثلاث أو الخمس القادمة؟
Try and push past your own life if you can
حاولوا وتخطوا حياتكم إن استطعتم
because it makes you do things a little bit bigger
لأن ذلك سيجعلكم تنجزون الأشياء أكبر قليلًا
than you thought were possible.
ممّا ظننتم أنه باستطاعتكم.
Yes, we have huge, huge problems out there.
نعم، لدينا مشاكل هائلة، هائلة في الخارج.
With this process, with this thinking,
بهذه العملية، بهذا التفكير،
I think we can make a difference.
أظن أن بإمكاننا أن نصنع فرقًا.
I think you can make a difference,
أظن أن بإمكانكم أن تصنعوا فرقًا.
and I believe in you guys.
وأنا أؤمن بكم يا رفاق.
Thank you.
شكرًا لكم.
(Applause)
(تصفيق)